Hey there! Ever feel like your English sentences are a little, well, basic? Today we're going to
こんにちは！英語の文がちょっと基本的すぎると感じたことはありませんか？今日は
unlock a kind of English superpower that's going to change all that. It's called the
その状況を変える英語のスーパーパワーを紹介します。それは
Two-Infinitive, and trust me, it's the key to expressing way bigger, cooler ideas. So,
「不定詞の二重形」と呼ばれ、より大きくてクールなアイデアを表現する鍵です。さあ、
let's get right into it. So, let me ask you a question. What do you want to be in the future?
早速始めましょう。まず、あなたに質問です。将来、何になりたいですか？
Maybe you want to become a famous YouTuber, or maybe you hope to play piano on a huge stage
有名なYouTuberになりたいですか？それとも、いつか大きなステージでピアノを弾きたいですか？
someday. Did you hear that? To be, to become, to play. You're already using this amazing grammar
聞こえましたか？「なる」「する」「弾く」。あなたはすでにこの素晴らしい文法
tool and you probably didn't even realize it. Okay, so to really understand our new superpower,
ツールを使っていますが、気づいていないかもしれません。さて、新しいスーパーパワーを
we've got to talk about the star player of every single English sentence, the main verb.
理解するためには、英語の文の主役、主動詞について話さなければなりません。
This is the main action, right? It's what's really happening. It's the foundation for
これは主なアクションです。実際に何が起こっているかを示します。それが
everything and you're already a pro at spotting it. Check this out. Super simple sentence.
すべての基盤であり、あなたはすでにそれを見つけるのが得意です。これを見てください。とてもシンプルな文です。
Small cats jump. So who are we talking about? The small cats. And what's their main action?
小さな猫がジャンプします。では、誰について話しているのでしょう？小さな猫です。そして、彼らの
They jump. Boom. That's our main verb, our star player. Easy peasy.
主なアクションは？ジャンプすることです。これが私たちの主動詞、主役です。簡単ですね。
But, you know, life is way more complicated than just that, isn't it? What happens when you want
でも、人生はそれだけではもっと複雑ですよね？同じ文で二つ目のアクションについて話したいとき、
to talk about a second action in the same sentence? You can't just have two star players
どうしますか？同時に二人の主役がフィールドにいるわけにはいきません。それは完全な混乱です。では、この文法の
on the field at the same time. That would be total chaos. So how do we solve this little
パズルをどう解決するのでしょう？秘密のエージェント、不定詞の二重形を呼びます。
grammar puzzle? Well, we call in a secret agent, the two infinitive. The formula couldn't
その公式はとてもシンプルです。基本動詞の前に「to」を付けるだけです。例えば、to run、to eat、to sleep。これは
be simpler. It's just two plus the basic form of a verb, like to run, to eat, to sleep. Think of it
隠れた動詞のようなもので、文をもっと面白くするための秘密のミッションです。
like a verb in disguise, on a secret mission to make your sentences way more interesting.
さて、この秘密のエージェントをテストしてみましょう。まずはとてもシンプルな
frame, okay? I want x, where x is just whatever it is you want. So a lot of the time that x is
フレームから始めます。「I want x」、ここでxはあなたが欲しいものです。多くの場合、そのxは
just a thing, a noun. For example, I want a new video game. Our main verb, our star player,
ただの物、名詞です。例えば、「I want a new video game」。私たちの主動詞、主役は
is want, and the video game is what we want. Pretty standard stuff, right?
「want」で、ビデオゲームが欲しいものです。かなり標準的な内容ですね。
But what if the thing you want is actually in action? Ha! This is where our secret agent
でも、もし欲しいものが実際にアクション中だったら？ここで秘密のエージェントが
totally shines. We just swap out the noun for our two infinitive. I want to buy a new video game.
大活躍します。名詞を不定詞に置き換えます。「I want to buy a new video game」。
And just like that, we have two actions working together in one sentence.
こうして、二つのアクションが一つの文で協力しています。
Want is our star player and to buy is our secret agent, making it all happen.
「want」が主役で、「to buy」が秘密のエージェントです。すべてを実現しています。
Ok, now this next part is super super important to remember.
さて、次の部分は非常に重要です。
Our star player, the main verb, it's kind of like a chameleon.
私たちの主役、主動詞はカメレオンのようです。
It has to change its form depending on who is doing the action, like I or he or she,
アクションを行う人（私や彼、彼女）や、いつ起こるかによって形を変えなければなりません。
and when it's happening.
例えば、主役がどのように変わるか見てみましょう。
For example, just look at how our star player, like, has to change.
「I」の場合は「likes」。彼の場合は「likes」になります。
If it's I, it's like. If it's he, it becomes likes.
そのSを追加しなければなりません。そして、過去形では「liked」になります。
You gotta add that S. And if we're talking about the past, it's liked.
分かりますか？動詞は常にルールに従って変わります。しかし、ここが一番のポイントです。
See?
秘密のエージェントの動詞が真のスーパーパワーを発揮します。
verb is always changing to follow the rules. But, and this is the best part, this is where
主役が常に変わっている間、不定詞の二重形はそのままです。誰が、いつであっても、
our secret agent verb reveals its true superpower. While that star player is busy changing all the
決して変わりません。本当に、見てください。主役は「like」から「likes」
time, the two infinitive, it just stays the same. I mean it, no matter who, no matter when,
「liked」に変わります。しかし、私たちの秘密のエージェント「to make」は、毎回全く同じです。
it never ever changes. Seriously, look at this, the star player changes from like to likes
「to make」「to make」「to make」、これがその力です。信頼できて、一貫していて、あなたの生活を
to liked. But our secret agent, to make, it stays exactly the same every single time. To make,
非常に楽にしてくれます。この秘密のエージェントを文の中でどう見つけるか？
to make, to make, that's its power. It's reliable, it's consistent, and it honestly makes your life
「to」という言葉を探してください。それは特別なタグのようなもので、文の他の部分に
so much easier. So how do you spot this secret agent in a sentence? Just look for the word
「次の動詞は主役ではなく、秘密のミッションに来ている」と伝えます。
two. It's like a special tag that basically tells everyone else in the sentence,
これで、あなたの新しい文法スーパーパワーが手に入りました。簡単に振り返りましょう。
hey, this next verb, yeah, it's not the star of the show, it's here on a secret mission.
第一に、その公式は常に「2 + 基本動詞」です。第二に、その役割は文に二つ目のアクションを加えることです。
So, there you have it. Your new grammar superpower. Let's do a quick recap. Number one,
第三に、黄金のルール。決して変わらないことです。これで力はあなたのものです。
its formula is always 2 plus base verb. Number two, its job is to add a second action to your
これで、より大きく、より良いアイデアを表現する素晴らしいツールを手に入れました。では、私の質問です。
sentence. And number three, the golden rule. It never changes. So the power is officially yours.
これを使って何を計画していますか？次に何を学びたいですか？
You now have this awesome tool to express bigger and better ideas. So my question for you is,
そして最も重要なのは、どんな素晴らしいものを作りますか？
is what do you plan to do with it? What do you want to learn next?
さあ、外に出て素晴らしい文を作り始めましょう。
And most importantly, what cool things will you create?
あなたならできる！